The Bling Ring is a drama, tv movie, crime film directed by Michael Lembeck.
At the center of one of Hollywood's most notorious burglary rings in 2009 was
a group of average, middle-class teens from a quiet suburb.
This is the behind-the-scenes story of how Nick, a shy, awkward boy, lured by the promise of popularity and acceptance, found himself following his
glamorous, charismatic best friend Rachel into breaking into celebrities' houses and robbing them of millions of dollars in clothes and jewelry.
Zack Garvey, played by Austin Butler.
Natalie Kim, played by Yin Chang.
Iris Garvey, played by Jennifer Grey.
Maddie Bishop, played by Spencer Locke.
Detective Archie Fishman, played by Tom Irwin.
Detective Jenks, played by Sebastian Sozzi.
The Bling Ring is a 2013 American crime film written and directed by Sofia Coppola featuring an ensemble cast led by
Emma Watson, Katie Chang, Israel Broussard, Taissa Farmiga, Claire Julien, Georgia Rock and Leslie Mann.
It is based on the 2010 Vanity Fair article "The Suspects Wore Louboutins" by Nancy
Jo Sales, which dealt with a real-life gang known as the Bling Ring.
The story follows a group of fame-obsessed teenagers who use the internet
to track celebrities' whereabouts to burgle their homes.
The film was an international co-production by producers in the United
States, the United Kingdom, France, Germany, and Japan.
Coppola began developing a screenplay based on the burglaries in December 2011, with Francis Ford
Coppola executive producing through American Zoetrope and Roman Coppola as producer.
She saw it as a departure from her previous works by focusing on a group of teenagers who are "products of our
growing reality TV culture", exploring consumerist tabloid culture and obsession with fame.
Casting took place in early 2012 with Coppola choosing
mostly young, unknown actors for the main roles.
Principal photography occurred between March and April
that same year in Los Angeles, California.
Brian Reitzell served as supervisor for the film's soundtrack and
co-wrote the musical score with Daniel Lopatin.
The Bling Ring had its world premiere on May 16, 2013, in the Un
Certain Regard section of the 2013 Cannes Film Festival.
In the United States, it had a limited theatrical release by A24 on
June 14, 2013, before opening wide one week later.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with many praising the cast and Coppola's
"stylish" direction; Watson in particular received critical acclaim for her performance.
Others criticized the film for its morally ambiguous
approach towards the subject matter.
The film grossed $20 million worldwide against its $8 million budget.
The Bling Ring represents the final work of cinematographer Harris Savides, who died of brain
cancer while the film was in post-production, to whom the film is dedicated.
The tone is emotional.